If you are planning to take health insurance, then
keep these three points in mind. If you do not pay attention, then
you may have to regret it later. You
can consider this as an exhausting video on health
insurance. If you watch this video
completely, then
I will tell you some things related to health insurance which
you did not know before because
very few companies were following it
or were able to provide it. It is a little different,
special and important video. Please like it right now. Let's
start
[Music]
See, I am keeping the first point very simple. The
second and third points are very
important. The first and basic point is
how to select health insurance. I am giving some important points.
If you keep these points in mind, then you will automatically
reach a good health insurance. See, the
first thing is that whatever health
insurance policy you are taking, there should
not be any kind of room rent capping. I mean, see what happens to it.
Sometimes we think that suppose I am
taking a health insurance policy in
which  There is a room rent capping of ₹1000000.
What will happen if you take a room of ₹20000, even
if it is for 4 days, then it becomes ₹0000 and I will pay
extra. This does not happen if there is a
cap on your room rent. Suppose
₹20000 is your actual rent. ₹1000000 is
your capping. You get a claim of only ₹1000000, which
means you get a claim of ₹50. There is a
capping of ₹50 on all your remaining expenses.
You will have to pay the remaining ₹50 majority expenditure
from your own pocket. Therefore,
whichever company's health insurance policy you
take, there should not be any kind of room rent
capping in it. The second important
point for you is the claim settlement
ratio. If you take a health insurance policy, you have
taken it so that when you
are on bed and your family needs money, the
insurance policy
provides money at that time.  What do you do?
Many times, we
save Rs. 10000 initially in the pursuit of a cheap policy,
but when the actual purpose
requirement is not met, then
what is the use of it?
Don't get carried away with Rs. 200000. Think long term. For what
purpose did you buy that health insurance policy?
That purpose should be fulfilled for you. So, the
claim settlement ratio, how many claims have come,
how many have passed the company, these are
important things to check. Next,
look at the bonus clause. Some companies
say that brother, whether you have any claims or not,
we will give you a bonus every year, 50% in the second
year, we will give you a bonus of 100%, which means
after two years, your sum insured will
double. There is also such a by-the-way policy.
Today, there are only one or two such policies in the market
that follow this, but you have to keep
this point in mind that the bonus should
not be such a gimmick that brother, I will
give you a bonus only when you do not make any claim.  You will
pay the first year, I will pay for 10, then I will pay for 5,
then I will pay for 5, and so on. In this way,
you will get a 100% bonus in 10 years. I do
n't need so much confusion. I have paid my premium.
As a customer, I have the right to receive a
bonus next year. If another company is able to pay,
we will ask for it. We would like to
receive the bonus. Initially, your sum insured may be
5 lakhs, but because of the bonus,
as soon as you receive that 100% bonus, your
sum insured will be 100%. We
want this. The next important point, you
can keep in mind is whether your health
insurance policy
covers Ayurvedic treatment or modern age treatment. Look, today we
cannot assume that
we will only take the traditional treatments that are
most necessary for us in times of crisis. We will
try to get that treatment. You too have to
insure this and take such a health
insurance policy. By the way,
if you want to take a health insurance policy,
want to compare it, want to study it, then
go to Policy Bazaar and
you can buy all the health insurance policies.  You
can check the policies, you will get the link in the description,
I will talk about it later
in this video, but to compare what is
available in which policy,
you
can study the policy market to study it at one place.
While selecting the next health insurance policy, you have to keep in mind the restoration
benefit. I had a sum insured of 10 lakhs,
I used it, so is my sum
insured getting restored again or not, is it getting restored
for the same disease
or not, is it getting restored for the same person or not, is it getting
restored,
before getting restored, my company is saying
that first exhaust the entire 10 lakhs, only then will
we restore it, or as soon as you
use even ₹ 7 lakhs, it is restoring it automatically,
you should know this point, it may seem
small to you, but it is very important,
see, in a 10 lakh policy, you got your first claim of ₹ 1 lakh,
you took ₹ 1 lakh from your policy,
how many ₹ 1 lakhs are left, what does the company
say  Second, your claim comes in for ₹10 lakh. The
company will say, "We will give you ₹10 lakh and only when your
entire ₹10 lakh is exhausted will we restore it." For
now, you pay ₹10 lakh yourself from your home.
Understood, understood? This was an important
point. If needed, please listen to this point again.
We do
n't want any ifs and buts in the restoration benefit. Lastly, there
can be small points like, are you
getting a preventive health checkup in your policy? Are you able to
go to your place and get a refund for the preventive health checkup? We should get this.
Plus, there are
some additional expenses whenever we get
admitted to the hospital - gloves,
utilities, food, are
all of that covered in our health insurance policy
or not. Obviously,
these should be important points.
If you keep this first point in mind,
you will have reached a good health insurance policy. The
second important point
that I want to discuss with you today.
That is maternity benefit with just three
months of waiting period. Your sum insured
can be 5 lakh, 10 lakh, 20 lakh, anything.
Your sum insured maternity
benefit will be paid to you immediately up to ₹5000000
on maternity. Today,
maternity benefit is not available in majority health insurance policies
and if it is available there, then the minimum
waiting period for you is 9 months.
You can avail maternity benefit on Policy Bazaar,
that too with just three months of
waiting period, which means even if you are 6 months pregnant,
you can still get this plan with maternity benefit.
Obviously,
you get regular health checkups in maternity plans. If we
talk about income tax, then you
also get income tax reduction there. If you
go to Policy Bazaar and buy any policy, then
you can avail your benefits there.  You
can get a dedicated relationship manager who will
help you in every step of the process. You will find the link to Policy Bazaar
in the description and PIN comment. You
also get 30 minutes claim support service.
But if you want to
take a maternity plan, there is a basic eligibility criteria for it,
which is appearing on your screen right now.
First of all, the woman i.e. the female should be
18 years or above.
Both the insured and their legally married
spouse and live-in partner should be covered
with the base policy. Now we move on to our
third and final point. Look at the Age
Report today, 70% of the Indians are
just a single medical bill away from
going into poverty. This means that if
they do not have a health insurance policy
and someone in their family goes to the
hospital, they will go into poverty. The
situation has become so bad that when we
talk about financial planning, the first thing that is important
for us is health
insurance, term insurance and
preparing an emergency fund. After that, we
talk about investments, but these people do not have
health insurance.  We ignore it and
think what will happen to me now,
what emergency can I face now, do
not do this. The final important point is
that the best time to buy a health
insurance policy was yesterday, the second
best time is today. As soon as you start earning your own money,
your family becomes
dependent on you. It is necessary for you to buy a family floater
health insurance plan.
Keep this point in mind. If you do
not buy this plan, you may
regret it later. Because these are the
basic rules of your financial plan, these are the basic
components. There is one more thing, just
keep this much in mind. While buying a health insurance policy, do
not get entangled in the trap of traditional plans or ULIPs. Many times you will
sit with an agent and you will feel like
buying a term plan and a health plan, he will
secretly push new types of plans to you. The
majority will be traditional plans or
ULIPs, we do not want that. We want pure
basic vanilla term insurance, pure basic
vanilla health insurance which is family
floater, this will complete our insurance
part, we have to keep this in mind. If you
like the video  Don't
leave without liking if you want to buy a health insurance policy
or want to study.
You will get the link to Policy Wizard in the description and pin comment.
Happy learning
and I will see you very soon.